TIFFANY LASTIMOSA

Seattle, WA | E-mail: lastimosa.ti@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/tiffanylast | GitHub: github.com/tifflastimosa | Website: tiffanycodes.me

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A skilled backend and full-stack Software Engineer with expertise in **Java, JavaScript, Python, C, RESTful APIs, and AWS**. Well-versed in object-oriented programming, data structures, algorithms, database schema design, and cloud environments. With 3 years of experience from education, ready to design, build, maintain, and enhance software applications.

SKILLS

Programming Languages:

Java (Spring Boot, J2EE, Apache Tomcat), JavaScript (React, Node.js, Express), Python, C, SQL, HTML, CSS

Technical Skills:

RESTful APIs, Microservices, Message Queues (RabbitMQ), Load Balancers, Caching (Redis), Distributed Systems, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Docker, Kubernetes, Version Control (Git, GitHub), Gradle, Maven, Postman, Relational Databases (MySQL), Non-Relational Databases (NoSQL), MS Excel

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Node.Js Open-Source Contribution

Sep 2023 – Present

- Proficiently address issues by crafting JavaScript solutions to enhance runtime efficiency.
- Thoroughly examine Node.js documentation to execute tests, ensuring the delivery of bug-free and impeccably clean code.

Ski Resort Scalable Distributed System (Project Repository)

Sep 2022 – Dec 2022

- Designed and deployed Apache Tomcat web applications servers, Java programs, RabbitMQ, and Redis to over 7 Linux virtual machines on AWS to create a scalable and robust microservice to maximize throughput and achieve low latency.
- Programmed a connection pool in the application server to reduce memory usage in system resources.
- Wrote a multithreaded Java program to concurrently send 200,000 POST requests and compute throughput statistics resulting in a 40 ms response time and a fault-tolerant distributed system.

Quantified Self Web Application (Project Repository)

May 2021 – Aug 2021

- Led a team of 2 engineers in Agile software development and test-driven development environment to build a web application with Spring Boot that would persist 1,600+ JSON objects from wearable technology to MongoDB and create a UI with React.
- Applied MVC architecture and object-oriented design to attain a quality average of 70% in the CodeMR metrics.
- Developed JUnit tests to achieve over 70% in code coverage and API tests in JavaScript to evaluate response times.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineering Tutor | Wyzant, Inc. – Bellevue, WA

Aug 2022 - Present

- Communicate effectively with 20+ students to discuss ambiguous technical problems, data structures, algorithms, software design, MVC architecture, the client-server model, and database schemas to design projects and implement code.
- Guide students in referencing third-party API documentation to strengthen the students' programming skills.

Operations Manager - Technology | Seattle Litigation Group, PLLC - Seattle, WA

Apr 2018 – Sep 2023

- Spearheaded the digital transformation of a small law firm to modernize data management and accounting by migrating operations to the cloud through SaaS solutions reducing the firm's annual accounting overhead from \$42,000 to \$10,000.
- Produced documentation for training and reference to ensure consistent operations within the law firm.
- Corresponded with 50+ clients to collect information and documents, ensuring HIPAA compliance, which was evaluated to create a course of action with the attorney to achieve the best outcome for 95% of clients.

Graduate Teaching Assistant | Northeastern University – Seattle, WA

May 2021 – May 2022

- Facilitated labs for 40+ students to build students' confidence in Java programming and object-oriented design.
- Reviewed and tested code for 10+ student assignments to ensure students achieved over 70% coverage in unit testing.

EDUCATION

Northeastern University

Seattle, WA

Master of Science in Computer Science | Cumulative GPA: 3.9/4.0

Sep 2020 – Dec 2022

Relevant Coursework: Data Structures & Algorithms, Object-Oriented Programming, Distributed Systems, Database Systems

University Of Washington

Seattle, WA

Bachelor of Arts in Anthropology: Medical Anthropology and Global Health, Diversity Minor

Sep 2008 – Jun 2013

CERTIFICATIONS & TRAINING